a very good evening ladies and gentlemen
my name is Ruth Morelli and I extend a
warm welcome to each one of you to this
very captivating intriguing and most
importantly a very relevant platform
called the business standard insurance
round table 2020
I'd like to call on stage Joe mr. Sharma
Majumdar editor business standard to
render a welcome note for all of us we
have completed 20 years of insurance
industry opening up to the private
sector the foundations for a buzzing
life and non-life sector was laid in
2000 so it's a good time to pause and
reflect the early years were about
establishing the business getting the
wallet share of a market that had only
dealt with government forms issues of
underwriting distribution disclosures
mis-selling and changing regulations the
next 20 years would be crucial as the
industry matures and deals with the
changing demographic technology
regulation and market order issues of
fraud risk of the unexpected externality
in the business and the Millennial mind
are some of the issues that the next two
decades will grapple with our
roundtables today is set against this
backdrop lessons learned in the past two
decades and the key disruptors and
game-changing initiatives that will
dominate this phase for the next 20
years
let me call onstage our illustrious and
noteworthy panel members beginning with
mr. Bhargav Das Gupta ICICI Lombard mr.
Inoue prowl future generally mr. Inoue
gelati honored Gulati Religare health
and mr. Sanjay Acharya martial India and
the person who is going to maneuver and
facilitate these discussion is going to
be mr. thummell Bandopadhyay a
consulting editor Business Standard we
are going to discuss the how the rules
of the game have changed post budget and
that was the time the insurance industry
if I may say so lobbying hard
the finance ministry for raising the FDI
FII limit from 49 percent to 74 percent
so many of them thought that this is
going to happen but what exactly
happened is completely different than
what was the expectation some numbers
where do we stand India and gel
insurance industry number four not in
the world in Asia till 2001 when the
industry opened up the CAG our is about
17% industry sizes 1.7 trillion and in
terms of percentage of GDP it's less
than 1% of GDP it's half of China global
average is 3 times India probably last
week IRDA chairman said that you guys
survived on your investment income when
it comes to underwriting it's all losses
so in this so with that not a very
pleasant thing I'll start with you you
know obviously you cannot disagree with
what I had a chairman said you know one
way of looking at it is you've made up
the underwriting losses through
investment income but the real story is
that if you look at a profit often types
of the industry in the same 11 years
it's actually become 1/4 so top line has
grown at a compound annual growth rate
of 17% the bottom line which is profit
after tax has reduced by 12% component
so the point is that you know if you
look at any insurance business in the
long term you have to focus on
underwriting profits because that's the
core of your business if you take
hundred rupees of premium you have to
make at least you know you know at least
you know 1 1 to be profit out of this
which means a combined ratio of 99 I
think what will happen if we sustain
this is that companies which are keep
which keep on losing money will
gradually become less and less relevant
and it'll you know industry will
unfortunately get more concentrated so
that's what markup does Gupta
the the boss of India's largest private
sector entity and the only listed entity
what you are saying is this predatory
pricing will kill some of the players
and consolidation we see the odd
achievement is right in saying the Priya
keep rising we'll end up taking the
industry the telecom way I think that's
the example he had used but I think the
fact is when you're fighting for market
share I think it's the laziest thing to
do is to compete on pricing or to
compete on commissions and it's at some
level it also displays lack of
imagination lack of innovation lack of
customer focus you know the issue is
that we sell commodity is not a great
proposition with the customer so unless
you actually revisit the way we look at
a customer this will continue to be a
challenge and frankly requires one read
rational player to give our rational
Commission's or prize it rationally for
maybe the second player to follow us
would then a third and a fourth then a
fifth and so on and so forth so it has a
domino effect and then you see that in
all markets and all segments all over
the world I mean I mean you have a lot
of companies you have tried to do with
that I think this problem will persist
so if you continue to be lazy about this
we'll have a larger problem thanks for
being so candid so gentleman we heard
about lazy banking now I know we're
saying is lazy insurance no no
imagination nothing you just know you do
the same thing in a mechanical way and
cut down the prices so what's your take
you are primarily in the health where is
a scope for innovation is much more as a
country give or take we spend close to
about six lakh crore rupees a year on
healthcare health insurance this year
will be about a sixty thousand crore
business right and in a lot of developed
markets most of this spend is either
financed by the government or comes in
from private health insurance so there
is a huge funding gap in India for
health insurance underwriting profits
are the only way to build sustainable
businesses so while there is a lot of
work we need to do collectively as an
industry because I think if you work
together from a supply side and I keep
saying there is demand most customers
are willing to buy it's our ability and
ability to supply or to make available
products at the right price in the right
way to the customer for Sanjay you are
different from them because they are the
insurers you are what should I call your
intermediary that's the right way right
the policy yeah representing
policyholder but primarily corporate
India right you are not into the retail
segment the copied India we serve close
to say five thousand corporates alone in
India and when we talk to them what the
policyholder says are these a couple of
things one they're asking for innovation
in the coverage so the coverage
improvement in India with regard to the
corporate India has not really happened
so regulator has allowed freedom in
coverage to the insurance market last
couple of years but the insurance market
has to take up this opportunity to start
giving teleMed coverage for different
industries far but what has happened in
the last couple of months is a very big
shock to the corporate India one hand
they are going through a downturn there
has been a change in terms of GIC led
reinsurance circular which makes the
pricing of property insurance on an
average for good risks in India by
minimum two times - as as much as ten
times
so the corporate India got used to
competition in pricing for last ten
years
but effective first-gen and the biggest
renewal coming in first April copper
India is going to be faced with no
competition in the insurance pricing on
the property rates so they are four so
for example pipeline roads they don't
want to have a full coverage for the
whole thing so many corporates and in
fact talking about that they don't want
to buy insurance so there was an and
many many corporates are discussing this
and this is a major development and
they're also complaining that the
experience of them on the claim speed
settlement for the Indian market has not
been strong and good enough but part of
just your quick reaction before you get
to the next round is this he said that
corporates will the companies will not
renew because of such a steep hike is
that correct you never watch the numbers
for April because that's when the
biggest involves happen but there's a
bit of a precedence to this because I
think I Sanjay said over the last 11
years in the property segment that we
are discussing prices have dropped by
more than 90 percent and I don't think
in India you've not seen you've seen
anywhere any segment where the prices
have collapsed to the extent that
labs and I think for corporate India one
of the biggest issues has been cost of
doing business and on the flip side our
insurance
I think Indian rates are less than half
of global rates even after B increase
this ayah D is the third regulator
globally after Singapore and UK and
globally is recognized as an extremely
progressive regulator which is
experimenting with regulatory sandbox
and demystifying what is regulatory
sandbox is actually allowing you to
experiment and experiment life in a
sense certain things are not allowed by
the regulator but if the experiments
succeed the regulations will be tweaked
and regulations will be changed to allow
you that product right so this so can
you give a sense where are we in this if
I may call it in the insurance lab at
this point of time given more new
digital mobile technologies allowing for
new product constructs as well as new
distribution methodologies or
distribution avenues becoming available
I think that's where sandbox becomes
even more interesting can you if it's
not confidential can you give us one
product that you guys have recommended
your company so he is experimenting for
approvals and I can talk about a couple
one we are doing is a most interesting
yeah the friendly sheron's product is
about where we can go to a set of so
let's say a group of cyclists who
regularly cycle together we believe that
nature of the risk there would be a
little different from the normal risk
because these are people are wanting to
keep fit on their own and so on so forth
so collectively for the group we would
be able to design & price the product
differently but there's one product we
have so we sell insurance and sashes and
let me explain what I mean by that yeah
so at future retail which is up which is
a promoter of a shareholder so at Big
Bazaar stores and all the future retail
stores we actually sell sachet products
our customer while checking another
counter can actually buy content
insurance somebody who's shopping can
achieve a cup of sachet and say that you
know buy a product to protect himself or
herself from mosquito-borne disease as
we call that a vector product
so here the innovation really has been
on the channel of distribution more than
products because I think we were told by
all and sundry that this will never work
because you know shops don't sell
insurance
I mean banks to agents do motor dealers
do but but in the last nine months
1 million products so one of the things
that I think as a country we should
worry about is road safety because India
is the accident capital of the world in
terms of number of deaths that we have
on the road and unfortunately over the
years we've not been able to design
products that incentivizes better
behavior so one of the products that
we've got approval for is a motor
insurance product where you pay your
premium based on the quality of your
drivers you can tell us how do you
decide the quality of driving like how
do I Drive depends on depends on you
know the speed that which at which your
drive you know sharp stop making no so
you put anything on the car you there is
there is a there is a obd device that
tracks the quality of your driving okay
and we even give you a score at the end
of this trip saying that this trip you
scored
you know you're driving score is this
and if you're driving score is poor your
premium will not go down if it's good
you know in the long term so you fix
that device on my car to Mecca